Guide to the Colin Davis Waterfront Workers Oral History Collection OH.060
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Colin Davis Waterfront Workers Oral History Collection
1995-1998
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Davis, Colin J (Colin John), 1954-
OH.060
1.25 Linear Feet in a CD box and an audiocassette box
614 kilobytes in 5 documents
Professor Colin J. Davis from the University of Alabama at Birmingham's School of Social Science and Behavioral Sciences recorded these interviews as part of a study of the New York City waterfront. Interviews were used in Davis' 2003 book Waterfront Revolts: New York and London Dockworkers, 1946-1961. The Colin Davis Waterfront Workers Oral History Collection (dated 1995-1998) contains seventeen interviews with longshoremen regarding their experiences working on the waterfront during the middle of the twentieth century. Additionally, there are four interviews with workers from the London, England docks: Pye, Donovan, Bloomberg, and Johns.
Conditions Governing Access
Materails are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Colin J. Davis in 2007. The accession number associated with this gift is 1950.049.
Arrangement
Materials in this collection are arranged alphabetically by last name.
Biographical Note
Professor Colin J. Davis from the University of Alabama at Birmingham's School of Social Science and Behavioral Sciences recorded these interviews as part of a study of the New York City waterfront. Interviews were used in Davis' 2003 book Waterfront Revolts: New York and London Dockworkers, 1946-1961.
Scope and Contents
The Colin Davis Waterfront Workers Oral History Collection (dated 1995-1998) contains seventeen interviews with longshoremen regarding their experiences working on the waterfront during the middle of the twentieth century. Subjects discussed include entry into the occupation, working conditions, characteristics of different cargoes, labor relations, relationship between rank and file union members and leadership, ethnic composition on docks, and Communist Party activity on waterfront. Interviewees worked in Manhattan, Brooklyn, and New Jersey. Additionally, there are four interviews with workers from the London, England docks: Pye, Donovan, Bloomberg, and Johns.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Stevedores |x Labor Unions; Stevedores -- New York (State) -- New York -- Interviews.; Working class -- New York (N.Y.)
- Frank Barbaro, July 6 and August 16, 1995
  Scope and Contents
  An electronic transcript is available.
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd Barbaro 1)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 1)
  - Partial Transcript -- July 6, 1995, TW_OH_060_ER_1
  - Partial Transcript -- August 16, 1995, TW_OH_060_ER_2
- Pete Bell, July 7, 1995
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd Bell 1)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 1)
- Joe Bloomberg, August 5, 1996
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd Bloomberg 1-2)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 2)
- Joe Bloomberg, August 7, 1996
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd Bloomberg 3)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 12)
- Leonard DiFazio, July 12, 1995
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd L. DiFazio 1)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 3)
- Sebastien DiFazio, July 10, 1995
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd S. DiFazio 1)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 4)
- John Donovan, August 9, 1996
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd Donovan 1)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 5)
- "Eddie", 1995
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd Eddie 1)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 6)
  - Partial Transcript, TW_OH_060_ER_3
- Ted Johns, July 11, 1996
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd Johns 1-2)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 7)
- Morris Klopot, July 13, 1995
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd Klopot 1-2)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 3, 9)
- Vincent Longhi, September 29, 1995
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd Longhi 1)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 8)
- Harold Mailman, June 12, 1998
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd Mailman 1)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 10)
- Angelo Pacifico, July 12, 1995
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd Pacifico 1)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 4)
- George Pye, August 14, 1996
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd Pye 1-2)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 11)
- Philip Sipser, June 29, 1995
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd Sipser 1)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 6)
  - Transcript, TW_OH_060_ER_4
- Larry Sullivan, July 13, 1995
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd Sullivan 1)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 9)
- Audrey West, June 22, 1995
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd West 1)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 14)
  - Partial Transcript, TW_OH_060_ER_5
- Jose Villa, Dec 16, 1996
  - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd Villa 1)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 103, Audiocassette 13)